Guide to the John Farquhar Fulton Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1914-1960; Series III
  - Writings [listed in the bibliography]
    - 31. Muscular Contraction and the Reflex Control of Movement (1926), pre-1926 (Box 265, Folder 50-58)
    - 32. "The Early Phrenological Societies..." (1927) (Box 266, Folder 59)
    - 43. "A Note: End-organs in Skeletal Muscle" (1928), 1927-1928 (Box 266, Folder 60)
    - 45. "A Clinical and Pathological Study..." (1928) (Box 266, Folder 61)
    - 47. "Observations upon the Vascularity..." (1928) (Box 266, Folder 62)
    - 59. "Emotional Disturbances Following Experimental Lesions..." (1929) (Box 266, Folder 63)
    - 63. "Edward Selleck Hare..." (1929)
    - 89. '"Dial' as a Surgical Anaesthetic for Neurological Operations..." (1930) (Box 266, Folder 64)
    - 90. "The Physiological Basis: Sympathetic Nervous System" (1930) (Box 266, Folder 65)
    - 91. Selected Readings in the History of Physiology (1930) [correspondence], 1929-1959 (Box 266, Folder 66-70)
    - 102. Physiology (1931), 1930 (Box 266, Folder 71)
    - 115. "A Bibliography of the Honourable Robert Boyle" (1932), Circa 1931-1932 (Box 266, Folder 72)
      See also: box 210, folders 252-255
    - 117. "Haller: Humanization of Bibliography" (1932) (Box 266, Folder 73)
    - 118. "Observations: Used as Surgical Anaesthetics" (1932), 1931-1932 (Box 266, Folder 74)
    - 119. "Claude Bernard and the Future of Medicine" (1932) (Box 266, Folder 75)
    - 120. The Sign of Babinski (1932), 1932-1933 (Box 267, Folder 76)
    - 124. "Robert Boyle: Thought in the Seventeenth Century" (1932) (Box 267, Folder 77)
    - 127. "The Influence of Unilateral and Bilateral Extirpation..." (1932) (Box 267, Folder 78)
    - 133. "The Nobel Prize: Sir Charles Sherrington" (1932) (Box 267, Folder 79)
    - 140. "Joseph François Félix Babinski" (1933) (Box 267, Folder 80)
    - 142. "The Warrington Academy..." (1933), 1932 (Box 267, Folder 81)
    - 143. "The Representation of the Tail in the Motor Cortex of Primates..." (1933) (Box 267, Folder 82)
    - 146. "Medicine" (1933) (Box 267, Folder 83)
    - 148. "William Beaumont's Letter to His New Haven Bookseller..." (1933) (Box 267, Folder 84)
    - 151. "Addenda to 'A Bibliography of Boyle'"
      See: box 210, folders 256-258
    - 152. Sei-ri gaku shisui (1933) [Japanese translation of Selected Readings in the History of Physiology ], 1931-1936 (Box 267, Folder 85)
    - 158. "Forced Grasping and Groping..." (1934), 1933 (Box 267, Folder 86)
    - Equality -- Bit by Bit, 1934 (Box 267, Folder 87)
    - 162. "Some Functions of the Cerebral Cortex" (1934)
      - Correspondence, 1933-1934 (Box 267, Folder 88)
      - Drafts, 1933-1934 (Box 267, Folder 89)
        See also: box 268, Folder 92
    - 164. "The Principles of Bibliographic Citation" (1934)
      - Correspondence, 1933-1939, 1954 (Box 267, Folder 90)
      - Drafts, 1933-1934 (Box 267, Folder 91)
    - 165. "Autonomic Representation in the Cerebral Cortex" (1934), Circa 1933-1934 (Box 268, Folder 92)
    - 167. The Nomenclature of Primates Commonly Used in Laboratory Work (1934) (Box 268, Folder 93)
    - 170. "Paralysis of Cortical Origin" (1934), 1934-1935 (Box 268, Folder 94)
    - 177. A Bibliography of the Poem "Syphilis sive Morbus Galicus" by Girolamo Fracastoro of Verona (1935)
      - Correspondence, 1933-1937 (Box 268, Folder 95-96)
      - Drafts, Circa1933-1935 (Box 268, Folder 97)
      - Notes on English editions, Circa 1933-1935 (Box 268, Folder 98)
      - Notes on French editions, Circa1933-1935 (Box 268, Folder 99)
      - Notes on Italian editions, Circa1933-1935 (Box 268, Folder 100)
      - Notes on Latin editions 1-10, Circa 1933-1935 (Box 268, Folder 101)
      - Notes on Latin editions 11-28, Circa1933-1935 (Box 268, Folder 102)
    - 179. "A Bibliography of Two Oxford Physiologists: Richard Lower 1631-1691 and John Mayow 1643-1679" (Box 268, Folder 103)
    - 183. "Joseph Priestly" (1935), 1932-1935 (Box 268, Folder 103a)
    - 184. "Somatic and Autonomic Motor Functions of the Cerebral Cortex..." (1936), 1935-1936 (Box 269, Folder 104)
    - 187. "Relation of the Cerebrum to the Cerebellum" (1936), 1935-1936 (Box 269, Folder 105)
    - 191. "A Bibliographical Study of the Galvani and the Aldini Writings on Animal Electricity" (1936)
      - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 269, Folder 106)
      - Drafts and notes, Circa 1935-1936 (Box 269, Folder 107-108)
    - 193. "The Interrelation of Cerebrum and Cerebellum" (1936), 1935-1936 (Box 269, Folder 109)
    - 197. "Cerebral Regulation of Autonomic Function" (1936), 1936-1937 (Box 269, Folder 110)
    - 199 and 202. "An Introduction -- Works of Joseph Priestly" (1936), 1937-1938; "Works of Joseph Priestly" (1937), 1933-1940 (Box 269, Folder 111-111a)
    - 205. "Humanism in Bibliography" (1937) (Box 269, Folder 112)
    - 207. Sir Kenelm Digby (1937)
      - Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 269, Folder 113)
      - Drafts and notes, pre-1937 (Box 269, Folder 114)
      - Drafts and notes, pre-1937 (Box 270, Folder 115)
    - 208. "A Note on Francesco Gennari..." (1937), 1937-1938 (Box 270, Folder 116)
    - 209. "Spasticity and the Frontal Lobes" (1937), 1937-1938 (Box 270, Folder 117)
    - 216. Physiology of the Nervous System (1938), 1945, 1958 (Box 270, Folder 118)
    - 225. "The Influence of Boerhave's Institutiones " (1938) (Box 270, Folder 119)
    - 226. "Cytoarchitecture of the Gorilla Brain" (1938) (Box 270, Folder 120)
    - 227. "A Projected Bibliographiaphysiologia " (1938) (Box 270, Folder 121)
    - 229. "Our Liberal Heritage" (1939), 1938 (Box 270, Folder 122)
    - 230. "A Style Book Containing Suggestions..." (1939) (Box 270, Folder 123)
    - 232. A Bibliography of the Writings of Harvey Cushing (1939)
      See also: box 212, folders 289-293
      - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 270, Folder 124)
      - Drafts and notes, Circa 1938-1939 (Box 270, Folder 125)
    - 234. "A Trip to Bohol in Quest of Tarsius " (1939), 1939-1940 (Box 270, Folder 126)
    - 236. "Medical Academies: Past and Future" (1939), 1938-1939 (Box 270, Folder 127)
    - 237. "An Exhibition Illustrating the Functions of the Frontal Lobes" (1939) (Box 270, Folder 128)
    - 243. "Harvey Cushing: An Appreciation" (1939) (Box 270, Folder 129)
    - 246. "The Physiological Basis of Cerebellar Syndromes" (1939) (Box 270, Folder 130)
    - 247. "Levels of Autonomic Function..." (1939), 1938-1939 (Box 270, Folder 131)
    - 250. "Dr. Harvey Cushing" (1940), 1939-1940 (Box 270, Folder 132)
    - 251. "Harvey Cushing. Resolutions..." (1940) (Box 270, Folder 133)
    - 252. The Hypothalamus and Central Levels ofAutonomic Function (1940), 1939-1940 (Box 271, Folder 134)
    - 263. "Experimental Studies on the Functions..." (1940) (Box 271, Folder 135)
    - 264. "England after the Air Battle of Britain" (1940), 1939-1940 (Box 271, Folder 136)
    - 265. "Neurology and War" (1940) (Box 271, Folder 137)
    - 266. Foreword to The Life of Sir William Osler (1940) (Box 271, Folder 138)
    - 269. Fisiologia del sistema nervioso (1941) (Box 271, Folder 139)
    - 270. "Medicine and the Sciences" (1941), 1939-1941 (Box 271, Folder 140)
    - 273. "Encephalization of Motor Functions..." (1941) (Box 271, Folder 141)
    - 276. "Recent Developments in Aviation Medicine" (1941) (Box 271, Folder 142)
    - 280. Introductory: Reflex Paralysis (1941), 1941-1942 (Box 271, Folder 143)
    - 281. "Blast and Concussion in the Present War" (1942), 1941 (Box 271, Folder 144)
    - 285. "Physiology and High Altitude..." (1942), 1941-1942 (Box 271, Folder 145)
    - 286. "The Development of Physiology in Connecticut" (1942) (Box 271, Folder 146)
    - 287. "A Five-foot Shelf on Aviation Medicine" (1942) (Box 271, Folder 147)
    - 288. "Medicine and Air Supremacy" (1942) (Box 271, Folder 148)
    - 290. A Bibliography of Aviation Medicine (1942), 1941-1942, 1945 (Box 271, Folder 149)
    - 299. Physiology of the Nervous System, 2nd ed. (1943) (Box 271, Folder 149)
    - Correspondence
      - 1940-1944 (Box 271, Folder 150-155)
      - 1945-1954 (Box 272, Folder 156)
    - 301. Introduction to "Vesalius Celebration" (1943) (Box 272, Folder 157)
    - 303. "Anoxia, pH Shifts and Central Nervous Function" (1943) (Box 272, Folder 158)
    - 307. "The Harvey Cushing General Hospital" (1944) (Box 272, Folder 159)
    - 308. "The Nature and Treatment of Blast Injuries" (1944) (Box 272, Folder 160)
    - 310. "Some Factors: 'Bends' at Altitude" (1944), 1943 (Box 272, Folder 161)
    - 311. A Bibliography of Aviation Medicine: Supplement (1944), 1940, 1944, 1954 (Box 272, Folder 162)
    - 316. "The History of Penicillin" (1944) (Box 272, Folder 163)
    - 319. "Speech at Celebration of the Seventieth Birthday of Arturo Castiglioni" (1944) (Box 272, Folder 164)
    - 321. A Bibliography of Visual Literature, 1939-1944 (1945), 1945-1949 (Box 272, Folder 165-166)
    - 326. "Penicillin, Plasma Fractionation..." (1945)
      - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 272, Folder 167)
      - Drafts, 1945 (Box 272, Folder 168)
    - 329. "Harvey Cushing, M.D." (1945) (Box 272, Folder 169)
    - 330. "Aviation Medicine..." (1945), 1944-1945 (Box 272, Folder 170)
    - 332. "The Historical Library, 1941-1945" (1945), 1945-1946 (Box 272, Folder 171)
    - 334. "Art Really Meets Medicine..." (1946) (Box 272, Folder 172)
    - 335. "The Letters: Cutter and Harvey Cushing" (1946) (Box 272, Folder 173)
    - 336. "The Housing, Care: Laboratory Primates" (1946) (Box 272, Folder 174)
    - 337. Harvey Cushing, a Biography (1946)
      See also: boxes 280-283, folders 294-349
      - Correspondence, 1939-1950 (Box 273, Folder 175-182)
      - Drafts and notes, pre-1946 (Box 273, Folder 183-185)
      - Drafts and notes, pre-1946 (Box 274, Folder 186-191)
    - 339. "Medical Societies and Medical Education" (1946) (Box 274, Folder 192)
    - 343. "History of the Yale Medical Libraries" (1946) (Box 274, Folder 193)
    - 344. "Science in American Universities..." (1946) (Box 274, Folder 194)
    - 346. "The Vision and Daring of Youth..." (1946) (Box 274, Folder 195)
    - 347. "Peacetime Implications of Wartime Medical Discoveries" (1946), 1946-1947 (Box 274, Folder 196)
    - 348. "Medicine Today: Its Assets and Liabilities" (1947), 1945 (Box 274, Folder 197)
    - 349. "On Being a Literary Executor" (147), 1946 (Box 274, Folder 198)
    - 350. "A Brief History of Yale's Medical School" (1947) (Box 274, Folder 199)
    - 351. "The Library of Arnold C. Klebs" (1947) (Box 274, Folder 200)
    - 352. "The Library of a Scholar: A. Klebs" (1947) (Box 274, Folder 201)
    - 354. "Physiological Basis of Frontal Lobotomy" (1947), 1947-1949 (Box 275, Folder 202)
    - 358. "Aviation Medicine..." (1947), 1945-1947 (Box 275, Folder 203)
    - 359. "Harvey Cushing's Early Training, 1884-1900" (1947), 1946 (Box 275, Folder 204)
    - 360. "Sherrington's Impact on Neurophysiology" (1947) (Box 275, Folder 205)
    - 361. "Edward Clark Streeter, 1874-1947" (1947) (Box 275, Folder 206)
    - 362. Preface to American Medical Research: Past and Present (1947) (Box 275, Folder 207)
    - 363. "Harvey Cushing and Arnold Klebs..." (1947) (Box 275, Folder 208)
    - 364. Benjamin Silliman ... (1947) (Box 275, Folder 208)
    - Book jacket, undated (Box 275, Folder 209)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1953 (Box 275, Folder 210-211)
    - Drafts
      - Preface and chapters I-VII, undated (Box 275, Folder 212-217)
      - Chapters VIII-XVII, undated (Box 276, Folder 218-222)
      - Index and bibliography, undated (Box 276, Folder 223)
      - Requests for permission of quotations, 1947 (Box 276, Folder 224)
    - 366. Physiologie du systeme nerveux (1947), 1947-1950 (Box 276, Folder 225)
    - 367. Second Addenda to "A Bibliography: Boyle" (1947), 1944-1948 (Box 276, Folder 226)
    - 368. "Cushing, 1869-1939" in Lesmédecins célèbres (1947) (Box 276, Folder 227)
    - 369. "Benjamin Silliman and the Founding of..." (1948), 1947 (Box 276, Folder 228)
    - 370. "The Surgical Approach to Mental Disorder" (1948), 1947-1948 (Box 276, Folder 229)
    - 373. "The Early Years of Andreas Vesalius" (1948), 1947 (Box 276, Folder 230)
    - 376. "Harvey Cushing and His Books..." (1948), 1947 (Box 276, Folder 231)
    - 378. "Notes on Some American Medical Libraries" (1948), 1947-1948 (Box 276, Folder 232)
    - 382. "Altitude Decompression Sickness" (1948) (Box 276, Folder 232)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1946-1951 (Box 276, Folder 233)
      - Contributors
        - B-J, 1946-1951 (Box 276, Folder 234-237)
        - L-W, 1946-1952 (Box 277, Folder 238-239)
      - Drafts, pre-1948 (Box 277, Folder 240)
    - 383. Aviation Medicine in Its Preventive Aspects (1948)
      - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 277, Folder 241-242)
      - Reviews, 1948-1950, undated (Box 277, Folder 243)
    - 384. The Frontal Lobes (1948) (Box 277, Folder 244)
    - 385. "Medical Progress" (1949), 1947-1948 (Box 277, Folder 245)
    - 386. Functional Localization in the Frontal Lobes (1949), 1949-1951 (Box 277, Folder 246)
    - 389. "Dr. Cushing and His Library" (1949) (Box 277, Folder 247)
    - 390. "William Osler, the Humanist" (1949) (Box 277, Folder 247)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 277, Folder 248)
    - Drafts, 1949 (Box 277, Folder 249)
    - 391. "Grace Revere Osler: Her Influence..." (1949) (Box 277, Folder 250)
    - 392. Physiology of the Nervous System, 3rd ed. (1949)
      - Correspondence, 1947-1959 (Box 277, Folder 251-252)
      - Reviews, 1950-1952 (Box 277, Folder 253)
    - 394. "A Prolegomenon to the Science" (1949), 1948-1949 (Box 277, Folder 254)
    - 395. "The Discovery of the Circulation" (1949) (Box 278, Folder 255)
    - 396. "William Osler as a Medical Historian" (1949) (Box 278, Folder 256)
    - 398. "Remarks upon Present-Day Electrocardiographic..." (1950), 1949 (Box 278, Folder 257)
    - 399. "The Brain as Organ of the Mind" (1950), 1947-1950 (Box 278, Folder 258)
    - 401. "Benjamin Silliman in His Lighter Moments" (1950), 1947-1949 (Box 278, Folder 259)
    - 402. "Rabelais and His Circle" (1950), 1949-1950 (Box 278, Folder 260)
    - 403. Humanism in an Age of Science (1950) (Box 278, Folder 260)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 278, Folder 261)
    - Drafts, 1949-1950 (Box 278, Folder 262)
    - 404. "Some Notes on the Yale University School of Medicine" (1950) (Box 278, Folder 263)
    - 405. Vesalius Four Centuries Later (1950), 1949-1951 (Box 278, Folder 264)
    - 406. "The Influence of European Teaching..." (1950) (Box 278, Folder 265)
    - 407. Foreword to William Osler (1950) (Box 278, Folder 266)
    - 410. The Great Medical Bibliographers (1951) (Box 278, Folder 266)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1953 (Box 278, Folder 267-268)
    - Drafts, pre-1951 (Box 278, Folder 269)
    - 411. Frontal Lobotomy and Affective Behavior (1951) (Box 278, Folder 269)
      See also: Series VI, Box 319, folder 4
    - Correspondence, 1950-1958 (Box 279, Folder 270-271)
    - Drafts and notes, 1949-1951 (Box 279, Folder 272-273)
    - 412. Decompression Sickness (1951), 1946-1950 (Box 279, Folder 274)
    - 415. Foreword to A History of Medicine (1951), 1950 (Box 279, Folder 275)
    - 416. "Some Aspects of Medicine..." (1951), Pre-1951 (Box 279, Folder 276)
    - 417. "Jules Baillarger and His Discovery..." (1951) (Box 279, Folder 277)
    - 419. "The 250th Anniversary: Yale University" (1951) (Box 279, Folder 278)
    - 420. "Yale University 250th Anniversary" (1951), 1951-1952 (Box 279, Folder 279)
    - 421. "The Impact of Science on American History" (1951), 1950-1951 (Box 279, Folder 280)
    - 423. "Lobotomy in Man" (1951), 1949-1951 (Box 279, Folder 281)
    - 424. "The Physiological Basis of Psychosurgery" (1951) (Box 279, Folder 282)
    - 425. The Frontal Lobes and Behavior (1952), 1950-1952 (Box 279, Folder 283)
    - 426. "Lewis Hill Weed" (1952) (Box 279, Folder 284)
    - 428. "Sir Charles Scott Sherrington" (1952), 1951-1952 (Box 280, Folder 285)
    - 430. Physiologie des Nerven systems (1952), 1948-1952 (Box 280, Folder 286)
    - 432. Foreword to Plan of a University (1952), 1953 (Box 280, Folder 287)
    - 433. Physiologie des lobes frontaux (1952) (Box 280, Folder 287)
    - Correspondence and notes, 1953-1954 (Box 280, Folder 288)
    - Draft, Pre-1953 (Box 280, Folder 289)
    - 435. "The Historical Contribution of Physiology..." (1953), 1945-1954 (Box 280, Folder 290)
    - 436. "The School of Medicine..." (1953), 1952-1953 (Box 280, Folder 291)
    - 437-438. "William Withering..." (1953), 1950-1953 (Box 280, Folder 292)
    - 439. "Somatic Functions -- Central Nervous System" (1953)
      - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 280, Folder 293)
      - Drafts, 1952-1953 (Box 280, Folder 294)
    - 440. Foreword to The Ciba Collection (1953), 1951-1953 (Box 280, Folder 295)
    - 444. "Arturo Castiglioni (1874-1953)" (1953) (Box 280, Folder 296)
    - 445. "The Library of Jonathan Knight (1789-1864)" (1953) (Box 280, Folder 297)
    - 446. "Gibbon: The 'unprofitable undergraduate'" (1953), 1953-1954 (Box 280, Folder 298)
    - 447. "Medicine in the Seventeenth and..." (1953), 1952-1953 (Box 280, Folder 299)
    - 448. "Michael Servetus..." (1953), 1952-1953 (Box 280, Folder 300)
    - 449. "Die neuromuskuläreübertragung" (1953), 1952-1954 (Box 281, Folder 301)
    - 450. "History of Medical Education" (1953) (Box 281, Folder 302)
    - 451. "Medicine, Warfare, and History" (1953) (Box 281, Folder 303)
    - 452. "The Limbic System..." (1953) (Box 281, Folder 304)
    - 453. "Notes on the History of the Postural Reflexes" (1953), 1952-1953 (Box 281, Folder 305)
    - 454. "Antoine Laurent Lavoisier's 'Réflexions..." (1953), 1951-1953 (Box 281, Folder 306)
    - 455. "A Bibliography of Galvani's Writings..." (1953), 1941-1942, 1952-1954 (Box 281, Folder 307)
    - 456. "Ramóny Cajal et la neurophysiologie" (1953), 1953-1954 (Box 281, Folder 308)
    - 458. "Contemporary Concepts of the Hypothalamus..." (1954), 1953 (Box 281, Folder 309)
    - 459. "Ralph Linton, 1893-1954" (1954) (Box 281, Folder 310)
    - 461. "Recent Advances in Neurophysiology" (1954), 1953 (Box 281, Folder 311)
    - 462. "Harvey Cushing as We Knew Him" (1954), 1953-1954 (Box 281, Folder 312)
    - 463. "Samuel Clark Harvey, 1886-1953" (1954) (Box 281, Folder 313)
    - 464. "Indirect Spinal Cord Injuries..." (1954), 1933, 1953-1954 (Box 281, Folder 314)
    - 465. "An Experimental Critique of the Effects..." (1954), 1953-1954 (Box 281, Folder 315)
    - 467. "Samuel Clark Harvey" (1954), 1953-1954 (Box 281, Folder 316)
    - 468. Preface to The World through Your Senses (1954), 1953-1954 (Box 281, Folder 317)
    - 469. "The Influence of British..." (1954), 1953-1954 (Box 282, Folder 318)
    - 470. Foreword to Doctors in the Sky (1954), 1954-1955 (Box 282, Folder 319)
    - 471. Preface to A Bibliography of the Works (1954), 1953 (Box 282, Folder 320)
    - 472. "Random Impressions: Castiglioni" (1954) (Box 282, Folder 321)
    - 474. "The Scientific Writings of Joseph Priestly" (1954), 1954-1956 (Box 282, Folder 322)
    - 475. "Louis H. Bauer and the Rise of Aviation..." (1955), 1954-1955 (Box 282, Folder 323)
    - 478. "Cortical Representation of Somatic..." (1955), pre-1955 (Box 282, Folder 324)
    - 479. Fulton Shinkeikei noseiri-gaku [Japanese translation of Physiology of the Nervous System ] (1955), 1951-1955 (Box 282, Folder 325)
    - 480. "Neurophysiological Backgrounds of..." (1956), 1955 (Box 282, Folder 326)
    - 481. "Egas Moniz (1874-1955), Nobel Laureate" (1956), 1955-1956 (Box 282, Folder 327)
    - 482. "Harvey Cushing, 1869-1939" (1956) (Box 282, Folder 328)
    - 483. "Charles Scott Sherrington, 1857-1952" (1956) (Box 282, Folder 329)
    - 486. "Sir Frederick Banting, 1891-1941" (1956) (Box 282, Folder 330)
    - 488. "Professor J. M. D. Olmsted" (1956) (Box 282, Folder 331)
    - 489. "Paolo Mascagni and the Lymphatics" (1956) (Box 282, Folder 332)
    - 490. "The Principles of Bibliographic Citation" (1956), 1955-1956 (Box 282, Folder 333)
    - 491. "Les fondements physiologiques..." (1956) (Box 282, Folder 334)
    - 492. "Reflections on the History of Reflex..." (1956) (Box 282, Folder 335)
    - 493. "C.-E. A. Winslow, Leader in Public Health" (1957) (Box 282, Folder 336)
    - 494. "Medicine and the Humanities" (1957), 1956 (Box 282, Folder 337)
    - 495. "Ashley Webster Oughterson" (1957), 1956-1957 (Box 282, Folder 338)
    - 496. "George Sarton and the History of Medicine" (1957), 1956-1957 (Box 282, Folder 339)
    - 497. "John Henry Bumsted, M.D., 1897-1957" (1957) (Box 282, Folder 340)
    - 498. "Completing Harvey's Work..." (1958), 1957 (Box 282, Folder 341)
    - 499. Foreword to My Friends the Librarians (1958) (Box 282, Folder 342)
    - 500. "Medical Aspects of Early Botanical Books" (1958), pre-1958 (Box 282, Folder 343)
    - 501. "Harvey Williams Cushing" (1958), pre-1958 (Box 283, Folder 344)
    - 502. "Joannes Gregorius Dusser de Barenne" (1958), 1956-1957 (Box 283, Folder 345)
    - 505. "History of Focal Epilepsy" (1959) (Box 283, Folder 346)
    - 506. "Ernest Sachs, 1879-1958" (1959) (Box 283, Folder 347)
    - 507. "Historical Reflections on the Background..." (1959), 1957-1959 (Box 283, Folder 348)
    - 508. "Die medizinische Bibliothek der..." (1959), 1959-1961 (Box 283, Folder 349)
    - 509. "Yale University School of Medicine" (1959) (Box 283, Folder 350)
    - 510. Foreword to Directory of the Medical Library Association (1959) (Box 283, Folder 351)
    - 511. "Charles Scott Sherrington, O.M." (1960) (Box 283, Folder 352)
    - 512. "William Willoughby Francis, M.D." (1960), 1959-1960 (Box 283, Folder 353)
    - 513. Preface to Henry E.Sigerist (1960), 1959 (Box 283, Folder 354)
    - 514. "Ramöny Cajal, Sherrington..." (1960), pre-1960 (Box 283, Folder 355)
    - 515. "The Honourable Robert Boyle, F.R.S. (1627-1692)" (1960)
      See: box 210, folders 259-263
    - 516. "Sir Kenelm Digby, F.R.S. (1603-1665)" (1960), pre-1960 (Box 283, Folder 356)
    - 517. Foreword to The Doctors of Yale College, 1702-1815 (1960), 1959 (Box 283, Folder 357)
    - 519. A Bibliography of Boyle
      See: boxes 210-212, folders 264-286
  - Writings [not listed in the bibliography]
    See also: Series VI, box 319, folder 4
    - 1914-1929 (Box 284, Folder 358-380)
    - 1919-1921: Collected Papers [submitted for the Merton Fellowship at Magdalen College]
    - 1925: "Some Aspects of Muscular Contraction" [essay for Warren Memorial Prize]
    - 1925: "Aspects of Muscular Contraction" [Ph.D. dissertation] (Box 285, Folder 381-386)
    - 1927: "Sanitary Survey of Salem"
    - 1929-1930: "A Clinical and Physiological Study of the Tumors of the Fourth Ventricle" (Box 286, Folder 387-399)
    - 1930-1936 (Box 287, Folder 400-434)
    - 1937-1939 (Box 288, Folder 435-466)
    - 1940-1943 (Box 289, Folder 467-501)
    - 1944-1948 (Box 290, Folder 502-547)
    - 1949-1953 (Box 291, Folder 548-580)
    - 1954-1958 (Box 292, Folder 581-611)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 293, Folder 612-626)
- Personal and Family Papers, 1884-1988; Series IV
  Series IV contains personal papers of John Farquhar Fulton and correspondence and memorabilia of other members of the Fulton, Langford, Wheatland, and Wheaton families. The series also includes genealogies and notes on family history. Correspondence of family members with John Fulton is filed alphabetically in Series I under the name of the correspondent. Files in the series are arranged alphabetically by the name of individual family members. Thereafter, materials are grouped according to record type.